Alex Santonastaso

London, UK | +44 7570 280428 | alex@santonastaso.com | github.com/snts42 | santonastaso.codes

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a background in Computer Science and Big Data Science. Experienced in building automation tools, data pipelines, and machine learning models using Python. I have a good understanding of APIs and cloud services, and I'm quick to learn new technologies on the job. I enjoy solving real world problems through efficient, maintainable code and collaborating to build great products and services.

SKILLS

Programming Languages & Tools: Python, Java, SQL, Git

Backend & Automation: Selenium, OpenPyXL, Pandas, REST APIs, Email Automation (SMTP)

Web & Frontend: React, HTML, CSS

Cloud & DevOps: GitHub Actions, Docker, AWS

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Team Collaboration, Effective Communication

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intech Centre (National Careers Service Partner)

London, UK

Python Automation Engineer

Jun 2024 - Present

- Built and deployed multiple Python automation tools using Selenium and Pandas to eliminate repetitive admintasks, reducing manual workload by over 30 hours per week.
- **Developed exam results processing system** for the City & Guilds Evolve platform, improving reporting speed, accuracy, and turnaround.
- Automated exam results emails by integrating Amelia API data, improving client response time and satisfaction.
- Automated data entry, form submissions, and reporting to support data-driven decisions and audit readiness.
- Managed enquiries, bookings, and scheduling for private courses and exams, maintaining smooth service delivery.

Queen Mary University of London

London, UK

Lab Demonstrator

Sep 2023 – Apr 2024

- Offered individual support to students in writing and debugging Python code for Machine Learning projects.
- Helped students understand software engineering concepts, including data structures and algorithms.

PROJECTS

Automated Facial Emotion Recognition

- Implemented facial emotion recognition using **GoogLeNet CNN**, achieving **high accuracy** on a deployment dataset and improving the model's capabilities.
- Prepared and pre-processed a FER dataset, including face detection, face alignment, data augmentation, image duplicates removal, and trained a second model for recognising emotions in blurred images.

Ethereum Blockchain Data Analysis

- Performed analysis on the raw high volume data of Ethereum blockchain by implementing a set of **Hadoop** and **PySpark** Map/Reduce operations such as aggregation, moving window technique.
- Implemented data visualisation using Matplotlib and Seaborn to present key insights and trends.

EDUCATION

Queen Mary University of London

London, UK

Master of Science in Big Data Science with Machine Learning Systems, **Distinction**

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

University of Westminster

London, UK Sep 2018 - Sep 2021

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, First Class Honours